Guide to the Oliver P. Merriman Scrapbook Collection, 1825-1942 CTC.1964.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Lettered Scrapbooks, 1870-1940; I.
  - Scrapbook M1, 1859-1940; 1880-1910 (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
    - John McCullough, 1880-1935; pages 7-22
    - Richard Mansfield, 1880-1940; pages 25-63
    - Robert B. Mantell, 1882-1936; pages 67-104
    - Henry Miller, 1891-1938; pages 107-132
    - Frank Mayo, 1880-1938; pages 135-143
    - Felix Morris, page 145
    - Ben Maginley, pages 147-149
    - B. Macauley, 1878-1888; pages 151-157
  - Scrapbook M2, 1877-1939; 1904-1939 (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
    - David C. Montgomery and Fred Stone, 1904-1916; pages 1-13
    - Elsie Janis, 1914; pages 7-10, 13,
    - Fred Stone, 1922-1938; pages 15-18, 19-24, 29-45
    - Dorothy Stone, 1925-1932; pages 19-33
    - Will Rogers, 1928-1929; pages 25-28
    - McIntyre and Heath, 1877-1938; pages 47-63
    - John Mason, 1913-1919; pages 67-69
    - Monroe and Rice, 1899-1939; pages 71-75
    - Murray and Murphy, 1887-1936; pages 77-79
    - Louis Mann, 1898-1931; page 81-87
  - Scrapbook M3, 1877-1942; 1904-1939 (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
    - John E. McDonough, 1877; page 1
    - Dominick Murray, 1878; pages 3-5
    - Joseph Murphy, 1883-1894; pages 7-9
    - Andrew Mack, 1899-1931; pages 11-13
    - Lewis Morrison, 1929; page 15
    - Burr McIntosh, 1937-1942; page 17
    - Willard Mack, 1926-1940; pages 19-24
    - Tom Meighan, 1936-1937; pages 25-30
    - Cyril Maude, 1915-1926; pages 31-47
    - Edward Morgan, 1904-1906; pages 49-51
    - Victor Moore, 1907-1935; pages 53-57
    - Frederick March, 1937-1939; pages 61-72
    - Grant Mitchell, 1920; page 73
    - Burgess Meredith, 1937; pages 75-78
    - Raymond Massey, 1938-1939; pages 79-89
  - Scrapbook M4, 1868-1938; 1898-1936 (Box 12, Folder 8-9)
    - Christie McDonald, 1912-1915; pages 1-7
    - Mitzi, 1919-1930; pages 9-19
    - Edna May, 1905-1906; pages 21-24
    - Ada May, 1922-1924; pages 25-30
    - Bessie McCoy, 1911-1931; pages 31-33
    - Raquel Meller, 1926; pages 35-37
    - Rose Melville, 1899; page 39
    - Marilyn Miller, 1925-1936; pages 41-54
    - Ruth Miller, 1928; page 55
    - Christine Miller, page 57
    - Florence Mills, 1925-1932; pages 59-60
    - Sadie Martinot, 1923; pages 61-65
    - Adah Menken, 1934-1938; pages 66-70
    - Mabel McKinley, 1909; page 71
    - Pauline Markham, 1919; page 73
    - Meigs Sisters, 1868; page 75
    - McGibeny Family, 1926; page 77
  - Scrapbook M5, 1874-1937 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - Maggie Mitchell, 1878-1927; pages 1-27
    - Clara Morris, 1874-1937; pages 31-39
    - Modjeska, 1878-1898; pages 47-64
  - Scrapbook M6, 1878-1935 (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
    - Jolly Nellie McHenry/Salsbury's Troubadours, 1878-1935; pages 1-25
    - Maggie Moore, 1879-1926; pages 29-32
    - Margaret Mather, 1883-1897; pages 35-45
    - Maggie Muhlanbring, 1879; page 47
    - Helene Mora, pages 49-51
    - Nellie Melba, 1895-1931; pages 53-59
    - Mary Mannering, 1896-1903; pages 60-61
    - Julia Marlowe, 1889-1927; pages 65-92
  - Scrapbook M7 - (M) Plays, 1865-1939; 1890-1935 (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
  - Scrapbook M8, 1868-1941; 1922-1941 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Stars, Companies, and Plays/Various, 1868-1933; pages 1-34, 45-47, 65
    - Stars and Companies/Marx Brothers, 1923-1941; pages 35-43
    - Stars and Companies/Paul Muni, 1933-1940; pages 55-63
  - Scrapbook N, 1876-1941; 1900-1936 (Box 13, Folder 8-9)
    - Olga Nethersole, 1894-1940; pages 1-15
    - Nazimova, 1908-1936; pages 17-34
    - Alice Nielson, 1899-1900; pages 35-37
    - Pola Negri, 1933; page 39
    - Fred Noss, 1936; page 41
    - Elliott Nugent, 1927; page 43, 49-50
    - J.C. and Ruth Nugent, 1927; pages 45-47
    - Milton Nobles, 1876-1930; page 51
    - Ermete Novelli, 1907; pages 53-54
    - Misc. N Plays, 1883-1941; 1910-1941; pages 55-86
  - Scrapbook O, 1877-1939; 1881-1936 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
    - John E. Owens, 1877; pages 1-9
    - James O'Neill, 1882-1923; pages 11-27
    - Chauncey Olcott, 1893-1933; pages 29-39
    - Nance O'Neil, 1898-1908; pages 41-45
    - Sigrid Onegin, 1929; page 47
    - Misc. O. Plays, 1881-1939; pages 49-105
  - Scrapbook P1, 1877-1941 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Tony Pastor, 1877-1940; pages 1-13
    - James T. Powers, 1894-1909; pages 15-25
    - Frederick Paulding, 1879-1937; pages 27-29
    - C.T. Parsloe, 1877; page 31
    - Corse Payton, 1926-1934; pages 33-36
    - Guy Bates Post, 1916; pages 37-38
    - Paderewski, 1937-1941; pages 39-58
  - Scrapbook P2, 1866-1941; 1890-1936 (Box 14, Folder 4-5)
    - Annie Pixley, 1879-1884; pages 1-11
    - Minnie Palmer, 1880-1936; pages 13-26
    - Adelina Patti, 1866-1904; pages 27-39
    - Carlotta Patti, 1872; page 41
    - Patrice, 1890; page 43
    - Ffolliot Paget, 1891; page 45
    - Eleanor Painter, 1921-1930; pages 47-49
    - Rosa Ponselle, 1919-1937; pages 50-55
    - Anna Pavlowa, 1921-1931; pages 57-63
    - Lily Pons, 1938-1941; page 65-71
    - Yvonne Printemps, 1934; pages 73-74
    - Mrs. Potter, 1895-1936; pages 75-77
  - Scrapbook P3 - (P) Plays, 1879-1942 (Box 14, Folder 6-8)
  - Scrapbook Q, 1879-1914 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Stars and Companies, 1879-1914; pages 1-9
  - Scrapbook R1, 1873-1926 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - John T. Raymond, 1873-1885; pages 1-15
    - Stuart Robson and Wm. H. Crane, 1875-1926; pages 17-45
    - McKee Rankin, 1878-1911; pages 47-67
    - George Fawcett Rowe, 1879; pages 69-71
    - John W. Ranson, 1883; page 73
    - George Rignold, 1877; page 75
  - Scrapbook R2, 1866-1939; 1894-1939 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
    - Roland Reed, 1876-1898; pages 1-7
    - Sol Smith Russell, 1866-1939; pages 9-29
    - Russell Brothers, 1894-1925; pages 33-37
    - Rogers Brothers, 1899-1932; pages 39-50
    - Forbes Robertson, 1904-1937; pages 51-68
    - Johnny and Emma Ray, 1894-1935; pages 69-73
    - Thomas W. Ross, 1907-1935; pages 75-82
    - Theodore Roberts, 1910-1924; page 83
    - Paul Robeson, 1926-1930; pages 85-88
    - Titta Ruffo, 1921; page 89
    - Rachmaninoff, 1927; page 91
    - Bill Robinson, 1939; pages 93-96
  - Scrapbook R3, 1868-1941; 1883-1936 (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
    - Rachel, 1936; pages 3-8
    - Madame Rejane, 1920; pages 9-10
    - Inez Rochelle, 1883; pages 11-15
    - Annie Russell, 1896-1936; pages 17-28
    - M'lle Rhea, 1883-1899; page 31
    - Fanny Rice, 1893-1936; pages 33-37
    - Ada Rehan, 1896-1927; pages 39-51
    - Parepa Rosa, 1868; page 1
    - Blanche Ring, 1910-1927; pages 53-59
    - May Robson, 1914-1941; pages 61-66
    - Florence Reed, 1923-1939; pages 67-80
    - Flora Robson, 1940; pages 81-82
    - Ginger Rogers, page 83
    - Marjorie Rambeau, page 85
  - Scrapbook R4 - (R) Plays, 1880-1942 (Box 15, Folder 5-6)
  - Scrapbook R5, 1929-1935 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Will Rogers, 1929-1935; pages 1-57
    - Program of Three Cheers, 1929; page 57
  - Scrapbook S1, 1877-1939; 1900-1936 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Sothern Family, 1877-1939; pages 1-71
    - Sothern and Marlowe, 1904-1928; pages 27, 33-39, 53-54, 57-60, 68
  - Scrapbook S2, 1875-1940; 1880-1925 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    - Barry Sullivan, 1875; page 1
    - John A. Stevens, 1878-1879; pages 3-5
    - Shannon and Edeson, 1880; pages 7-9
    - W.J. Scanlan, 1884; pages 11-13
    - J.C. Stewart, 1884-1940; page 15
    - Dan'l Sully, 1887-1933; pages 17-19
    - Tomaso Salvini, 1880-1881; pages 21-23
    - Alexander Salvini, 1895; pages 25-29
    - Thomas Q. Seabrooke, 1892-1895; pages 31-35
    - Sandow, 1894-1925; pages 37-44
    - Jerome Sykes, 1900-1902; pages 45-51
    - J. H. Stoddart, 1904-1907; pages 53-55
    - Cyril Scott, 1906; page 57
    - Basil Sydney, 1923-1929; pages 59-61
    - Joseph Stanley, 1925-1928; pages 63-66
    - Lowell Sherman, 1925; page 67
    - Charles "Chic" Sale, 1934-1936; pages 69-71
  - Scrapbook S3 - (S) Plays, 1856-1935; 1882-1930 (Box 16, Folder 3-4)
  - Scrapbook S4 - (S) Plays, 1877-1941; 1923-1941 (Box 16, Folder 5-6)
  - Scrapbook S5, 1894-1942; 1922-1942 (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
    - Skinner, Cornelia and Otis, 1894-1942; 1922-1942; pages 1-74
  - Scrapbook S6, 1879-1941; 1904-1941 (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
    - Dora Gordon Steeles, 1879; page 1
    - Scott Siddons, 1880; page 3
    - Emily Soldene, page 5
    - Carrie Swain, 1883; page 7
    - Lillian Spencer, 1883-1923; page 9
    - Mme Ernestine Shumann-Heink, 1920-1936; pages 11-28
    - Mary Shaw, 1905-1929; pages 29-34
    - Fritizi Scheff, 1904-1937; pages 35-45
    - Frances Starr, 1908-1937; pages 47-61
    - Rose Stahl, 1908-1912; pages 63-65
    - Ann Swinburne, 1914; page 67
    - Marguerita Sylva, 1912-1938; pages 68-69
    - Ruta St. Denis, 1923-1941; pages 71-73
    - Julia Sanderson, 1909-1935; pages 75-87
  - Scrapbook T1, 1871-1941; 1892-1939 (Box 17, Folder 5-6)
    - Charlotte Thompson, 1874-1885; pages 1-11
    - Lydia Thompson, 1871-1889; pages 13-17
    - Kate Thayer, 1879; page 19
    - Corra Tanner, 1889-1890; pages 21-23
    - Fay Templeton, 1884-1939; pages 25-55
    - Marie Tempest, 1892-1938; pages 57-66
    - Laurette Taylor, 1910-1939; pages 67-76
    - Ellen Terry, 1907-1937; pages 77-80
    - Emma Trentini, 1911-1914; pages 81-86
    - Mabel Taliaferro, 1909; page 87
    - Sarah Trux, 1902-1903; pages 89-95
    - Evelyn Nesbit Thaw, 1902-1913; pages 97-100
    - Marion Talley, 1926-1927; pages 101-104
    - Sybil Thorndike, page 105
    - Eva Tanguay, 1941; pages 106-107
  - Scrapbook T2, 1878-1942 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Denman Thompson, 1880-1942; pages 1-21
    - Thurston, 1926-1937; pages 23-36
    - Charles R. Thorne, 1878; page 37
    - Sir Herbert Tree, 1917-1937; pages 39-40
    - George Thatcher, 1893; page 41
    - Ernest Truex, 1925-1940; pages 43-45
    - Lawrence Tibbett, 1936-1941; pages 47-49
  - Scrapbook T3 - (T) Plays, 1880-1942; 1923-1940 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook T4 - (T) Plays, 1879-1941; 1910-1940 (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
  - Scrapbook U1 (Box 18, Folder 3-4)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, 1874-1941; pages 1-70
  - Scrapbook U2, 1889-1935 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Lenore Ulric, 1919-1935; pages 1-18, 32
    - Misc. U Plays, 1889-1915; pages 19-31
  - Scrapbook V, 1868-1940; 1904-1940 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Henry Vincent, 1868; page 1
    - Von Stamwitz, 1877; pages 3-9
    - Mattie Vickers, 1883; page 11
    - Rosina Vokes, pages 13-20
    - Grace Van Studdiford, 1904-1927; pages 21-27
    - V Plays, 1926-1940; pages 29-48
  - Scrapbook W1, 1885-1938 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - E.S. Willard, 1892-1938; pages 1-21
    - Francis Wilson, 1885-1935; pages 23-59
    - David Warfield, 1902-1922; pages 61-79
    - Tom Wise, 1923-1928; pages 81-85
  - Scrapbook W2, 1883-1940 (Box 18, Folder 8-9)
    - Wilbur Opera Company, 1883-1938; pages 1-9
    - George Whites' Scandals, 1925-1940; pages 11-29
    - Ed Wynn's Shows, 1921-1940; pages 31-55
  - Scrapbook W3, 1865-1938; 1896-1934 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
    - William Warren, 1873; pages 1-2
    - Artemus Ward, 1865-1934; pages 3-9
    - Frederick B. Warde, 1878-1935; pages 11-30
    - John F. Ward, 1883; page 31
    - Walker Whiteside, 1896-1938; pages 33-44
    - Charles Warner, 1904; page 45
    - H.B. Warner, 1911-1924; pages 47-49
    - Walter Woolf, 1929-1932; pages 51-54
    - Reinald Werrenrath, 1927; pages 55-56
    - Paul Whiteman, 1924; page 57
    - Al H. Wilson, 1912; page 59
  - Scrapbook W4, 1869-1941; 1903-1937 (Box 19, Folder 3-4)
    - Minnie, Jennie, and Maude Wallace, 1869; page 1
    - Emma Waller, 1877; page 3
    - Bertha Welby, 1884; pages 5-7
    - Marie Wainwright, 1891-1923; pages 9-20
    - Blanche Walsh, 1903-1920; pages 21-30
    - Hattie Williams, 1908-1910; pages 31-33
    - Helen Ware, 1914-1939; pages 35-37
    - Charlotte Walker, 1914-1920; pages 39-42
    - Mae West, 1926-1937; pages 43-56
    - Ethel Waters, 1932-1941; pages 57-72
  - Scrapbook W5, 1889-1942; 1899-1912 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Weber and Fields, 1889-1942; pages 1-56
    - De Wolf Hooper, 1901-1902; pages 9, 11, 21-25
    - David Warfield, 1899-1901; pages 9, 21-30
    - John T. Kelly, 1899-1912; pages 9, 11-21, 25-27
    - Lillian Russell, 1899-1912; pages 9, 11-27
    - Fanny Dupre, 1901; pages 9
  - Scrapbook W6, 1880-1941; 1898-1941 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Bert Williams, 1922-1932; pages 21-23
    - Gus Williams, 1880-1885; pages 1-7
    - Ward & Vokes, 1898-1936; pages 9-17
    - Williams & Walker, 1899; page 19
    - Tom Waters, 1934-1939; pages 25-30
    - Way Down East, 1898-1941; pages 31-47
  - Scrapbook W7 - (W) Plays, 1877-1940; 1885-1936 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - The World, 1881; page 1
    - The Wife, 1890; pages 3, 7
    - The White Steed, 1939; pages 87-90
    - Workmen of Pittsburgh, 1877; page 93
    - W Plays/Various, 1885-1940; page 5, 9-86, 91-92
  - Scrapbook W8, 1890-1893 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Unmounted Programs, Harry Williams Academy, 1890-1893
  - Scrapbook W9, 1893-1896 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Unmounted Programs, Harry Williams Academy, 1893-1896
  - Scrapbook XYZ, 1907-1938 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Ronald Young, 1921; page 5
    - Clara Kimball Young, 1920; page 1
    - Ziegfeld Follies, 1907-1937; pages 3, 33-92
    - Y Plays/Various, 1922-1938; pages 9-31
    - Z Plays/Various, 1927-1938; pages 93-98
- Numbered Scrapbooks, 1825-1942; II.
  The scrapbooks in this series were assigned numbers by Mr. Merriman. There is no known reason why some subjects were given their own number and why others were given a sub-divided number/letter combination. As with the other scrapbooks in the collection these contain theatre programs, newspaper and magazine clippings, photographs, and other ephemera.
  - Scrapbook 10 - Famous Producers, 1925-1942; pages 1-90 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook 14 - Actresses, 1896-1940; 1922-1940 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Mrs. Whiffen, 1924-1936; pages 1-24, 81
    - Jennie Eustace, 1936; pages 25-26
    - Genevieve Ward, 1922; page 27
    - Ada Boshell, 1922-1924; pages 29-30
    - Jennie, Stella, and Kate Mayhew, 1934-1936; pages 31-35
    - Maggie Cline, 1929-1938; pages 37-39
    - Jenny Lind, 1925-1936; pages 41-52, 88
    - Mrs. G. M. Gilbert, pages 53-54
    - Frankie Bailey, 1927; page 55
    - Fanny Brice, pages 57-60
    - Mary Blair, 1935-1937; pages 61-62
    - Marian Storm, 1937; page 63
    - May Yohe, 1896-1939; pages 65-68, 82-83
    - Alison Skipworth, 1938; page 69
    - Hetty Green, 1940; pages 75-78
    - Minnie Dupree, 1920; pages 79-80
    - Edna Ferber, 1939; pages 73-74
    - Hattie McDaniel, 1940; page 84
    - Mme. Recamier, 1940; page 86
  - Scrapbook 15 - Theatre Articles, 1853-1940; 1902-1940 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Brander Matthews, 1894-1925; pages 1-12, 79
    - F. F. Mackay, 1923; pages 13-14
    - J. J. McCloskey, page 15
    - Antonio Scotti, 1926-1936; pages 17-27
    - John Bunny, 1915; pages 29-30
    - Sir James Barrie, 1927-1937; pages 31-34, 41-48
    - Bill Hart, 1902-1940; pages 35-37, 77-78
    - Frank Frayne, 1929-1938; page 39
    - Victor Moore, 1939; page 49
    - Thomas Hamblin, 1853; page 51
    - Don Marquis, 1937-1939; pages 53-54
    - George Bernard Shaw, 1902; page 55
    - Buddy De Sylva, 1940; pages 57-67
    - Munseys, 1894-1895; pages 69-73
    - Bert Lahr, 1939-1940; pages 75-76
  - Scrapbook 16 - Theatre Articles, 1894-1941 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Marc Connelly, 1936; pages 5-6
    - Eugene Connelly, 1906-1936; pages 2-4, 87-89
    - Harry Davis, 1903-1939; page 7
    - Erasmus Wilson, 1894-1938; pages 9-12
    - W.W. Fullwood, 1898-1920; pages 13-15
    - John Kane, 1936-1938; pages 17-25
    - Morris W. Mead, 1938-1941; page 27
    - Arthur G. Burgoyne, 1911-1940; page 29
    - Charles H. L. Orton, page 32
    - Thomas Jefferson Smith, 1900; page 32
    - Edwin Bedder, page 33
    - James M. Kirkland, 1936-1940; page 35
    - Howard Johnson, 1935-1937; pages 37-40
    - Dr. Edmund Weidlein, 1933-1936; pages 41-42
    - Vincent Nesbert, 1936; pages 43-44
    - Emil Foerster, 1933; page 45
    - Martin Leisser, 1937-1940; pages 49-52
    - Poet Realf, 1937; page 53
    - Jackson D. Haag, 1938; page 57
    - Robert Garland, 1939; page 59
    - Frank Denton, 1932; page 61
    - George Smith, 1940; pages 63-78
    - Chancellor John Bowman, 1941; page 79
    - Carl Bernathaler, 1909; page 81
    - Charles Heinroth, 1927-1941; page 83-84
    - Emil O. Wolff, 1912; page 85
    - Nixon, 1907-1940; page 1, 55
  - Scrapbook 19 - Non-Theatre, 1874-1941; 1936-1940 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    The vast majority of this scrapbook relates to non-theatre related female personalities of the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. It includes materials on Clara Barton, Hellen Keller, Nellie Bly, etc. It is believed that the only reason this volume was not retained by the Carnegie Library was that there are a few pages devoted to Rosemary Casey, a Pittsburgh playwright.
    - Non-Theatre, 1874-1941; 1936-1940; pages 1-94
    - Rosemary Casey, 1934-1938; pages 95-102
  - Scrapbook 19B - Strawhat programs, 1871-1942; 1937-1942; pages 1-50 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook 20 - Theatre Architecture, 1875-1937; 1900-1937; pages 1-49 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook 20B - New York theatres, 1870-1940; 1920-1940 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Gramercy Park, 1940; page 1
    - Casino Theatre, pages 3-8
    - Academy of Music, 1925; pages 9-10
    - Criterion Theater, 1935; page 11
    - The Thalia Theatre, 1925-1929; pages 13-14
    - Steinway Hall, 1925; pages 17-20
    - Broadway Theatre, 1927; page 21, 31
    - Hippodrome, 1909; pages 23-25, 77
    - Eden Musee, 1898; page 27
    - Wallack Theatre, 1940; page 32
    - Century Theatre, 1928-1930; page 33
    - The Empire Theatre, 1938; page 29
    - Images, 1940; pages 35-41
    - The Bowery, 1925-1931; pages 43-52, 67-68
    - Central Park Flyer, page 53
    - Scribner's Monthly, 1870-1902; pages 55-66
    - The Crystal Palace, 1939; page 69
    - The World Article, 1889; page 71
    - Sunday Mirror Magazine Article, 1940; pages 73-74
    - Hammersteins, page 75
    - Capitol Theatre, 1920; page 15
    - Metropolitan, 1941; page 78
  - Scrapbook 44A - Early Theatre Ads, 1825-1937; 1876-1934; pages 1-120 (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
  - Scrapbook 44B - Stories of the Stage, 1907-1941; pages 1-128 (Box 22, Folder 3-4)
  - Scrapbook 44C - Articles of Theatre and Theatre Folk, 1878-1940; 1903-1940; pages 1-56 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook 45B - Inaugural Programs, 1888-1940; pages 1-42 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook 51A - Photographs, 1847-1939; pages 1-90 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook 51B - Photographs, 1892-1936; pages 1-124 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
  - Scrapbook 51C - Photographs, 1861-1940; pages 1-92 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook 54 - John Wilkes Booth, 1864-1941; 1912-1941; pages 1-44 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook 57 - Various Theatre Articles, 1878-1941; 1924-1941; pages 1-38 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Carmen, 1878-1925; pages 11-17
    - Camille, 1924-1937; pages 19-27
  - Scrapbook 59 - Carnegie Institute of Technology Programs, 1915-1941; pages 1-74 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook 59A- Carnegie Institute of Technology Programs, 1877-1935; 1924-1935; pages 1-32 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Dated Scrapbooks, 1859-1942; III.
  The Dated Scrapbook series is pretty straight forward in its organization. The series contains Pittsburgh theatre programs arranged in chronological order. Note that while all the programs date from the time span listed in the title of the folder, the dates of the newspaper clippings and accompanying items stretch into the 1930s and 1940s.
  - Scrapbook 1859-1880 - Local Programs (Pittsburgh), 1859-1938; 1859-1879; pages 1-82 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook 1881-1900 - Local Programs (Pittsburgh), 1881-1940; pages 1-76 (Box 24, Folder 6-7)
  - Scrapbook 1881-1900 no. 2 - Non-Professional Local Programs (Pittsburgh), 1879-1938; 1883-1898; pages 1-64 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook 1919-1929 - Local Programs (Pittsburgh), pages 1-68 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook 1930-1935 - Local Programs (Pittsburgh), 1930-1942; pages 1-79 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Pittsburgh Drama League, 1931-1932; pages 17-18, 21
    - White Star Adriatic and Georgic concert, 1932; page 27
    - Pitt Players, 1933; page 33
    - Pittsburgh Drama League, 1933; pages 35, 43
    - University of Pittsburgh Cap and Gown Club, 1933-1935; pages 39-40, 68
  - Scrapbook 1936-1941 - Amateur and Semi-Professional Local Theatres (Pittsburgh), pages 1-74 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Coded Scrapbooks, 1866-1941; IV.
  This series contains several sets of scrapbooks that are grouped by subject and then were given an abbreviated title. The first two volumes of scrapbooks (SEP and LIB) contain articles clipped from the Saturday Evening Post, Liberty Magazine, and Colliers. It should be noted that Merriman used different paper for "the Ideal Scrapbook," this paper and the contents glued to it are extremely brittle. This scrapbook contains the same types of materials from both Pittsburgh and New York elsewhere in the collection, but is ordered chronologically. One difference is that whole Broadway booklet programs are pasted onto the pages, rather than just the necessary program information clipped out.
  - Scrapbook SEP - Saturday Evening Post, 1924-1927; pages 1-130 (Box 25, Folder 4, Box 26, Folder 1)
    - George Cohan, 1926; pages 1-16
    - Nellie Melba, 1925; pages 17-50
    - John Philip Sousa, 1925-1927; pages 51-80
    - Elisabeth Marbury, 1925; pages 81-94
    - Weber and Fields, 1924; pages 95-130
  - Scrapbook LIB - Liberty Magazine and Colliers, 1927-1929; pages 1-340 (Box 26, Folder 2-7)
    - Leslie Carter's Portrait of a Lady with Red Hair, 1927; pages 1-90
    - What Stars are Made of by John K. Winkler, 1927; pages 91-94
    - Front-Page Drama or Stage Tales of Two Cities by Burns Mantle, 1927; pages 95-100
    - The Folio in the Life of Oscar Hammerstein by George Blumenthal and Bruce Grant, 1927; pages 101-103
    - Those in Peril by P. G. Wodehouse, 1927; page 104
    - Mary Garden's Battles with Hammerstein by George Blumenthal and Bruce Grant, 1927; pages 105-108
    - Mad Music Mad Money by George Blumenthal and Bruce Grant, 1927; pages 109-112
    - An Enemy of Women by George Blumenthal and Bruce Grant, 1927; pages 113-116
    - The Twilight of the Gods by George Blumenthal and Bruce Grant, 1927; pages 117-120
    - I Fought Them All by Tom Sharkey and Hugh Fullerton, 1927; pages 121-154
    - The Dean of Custard College by Rob Wagner, 1927; pages 155-167
    - From Dancing Shoes to Baby Shoes by Elsie Janis, 1927; pages 168-170
    - Things We Remember by Irene Castle, 1928; pages 171-194
    - The Nickel Shocker by Walter Davenport, 1928; pages 195-202
    - The Dirt Disher by Walter Davenport, 1928; pages 203-210
    - Baseball's Blackest Day by Hugh Fullerton, 1928; pages 211-212
    - The Hit That Broke the Browns by Hugh Fullerton, 1928; pages 213-215
    - When the Gamblers were Routed by Hugh Fullerton, 1928; page 216
    - The Game that Stirred the Nation by Hugh Fullerton, 1928; pages 217-219
    - Big Del's 4 Homers by Hugh Fullerton, 1928; pages 220-222
    - The Greatest Inning Ever Played by Hugh Fullerton, 1928; pages 223-224
    - The Life Story of Barbara La Marr by Adela Rogers St. Johns, 1928; pages 225-252
    - Nothing Up My Sleeve by Thurston the Magician, 1929; pages 253-296
    - The Jersey Lily by Princess Alexandra Kropotikin, 1929; pages 297-340
  - Scrapbook Ideal (New York and Pittsburgh) - Programs and Articles, 1909-1915; pages 1-54 (Box 26, Folder 8-10)
  - Scrapbook Stock - Stock and Repertory Productions, 1895-1904; pages 1-30 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - The Avenue Opera Company, 1895-1896; page 1
    - Casino Theatre, 1896; pages 3-5
    - The Duquesne Garden, 1900-1903; pages 7, 11-21, 27-30
    - The Avenue Theatre, 1904; pages 23-25
  - Scrapbook Davis - Harry Davis Productions, 1896-1940; pages 1-94 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - The Avenue Theatre, 1896-1900; pages 1-21, 39-51, 89
    - Grand Opera House, 1897-1901; pages 23-37, 53-67